The posterior hand is slightly lower than the anterior hand which is slightly
higher.
Because my lung is making this rocking movement on its axis.
A movement like this and makes a movement like that.
But at the same time, I place myself in its embryonic field.
So, I am looking for its embryonic fulcrum point.
Its embryonic fulcrum point is this aspirational field.
So I seek to move into this motion to repotentialize it in its primary function.
That is to say.
to be ready to take the breath of life.
All the development during the nine months of embryonic development
prepares it for this first movement.
Do you know what the lungs produce in the embryonic stage?
Amniotic fluid.
The lungs will resume a function of producing amniotic fluid
which is very important because the embryo is nestled and drinks this fluid.
It’s like a great autocrine communication.
I also check in with my kidneys.
Part of this amniotic fluid in the sac of the bones will also be urine.
There will be what we call a specific protein known as surfactant,
which will be produced a bit later, allowing your lungs to open at
the moment of birth.
At first, my pressure is quite gentle.
I just need to gradually find that bubble where the lung can
organize.
I simply give it space to organize and feel free.
At the level of the pulmonary hilum, between the visceral pleura and the parietal pleura,
I have this meeting between my trachea, my bronchus, and this beautiful interaction
between an air bronchial tissue that contains air, that contains a volume
of residual gas, and beside it is all this liquid space, there
is a small frequency,
there we enter a tissue where a past sadness is protected, it has found a
birth.
I want to bring myself over it, so I'm going to move slowly.
And there, if we go, the tissue may begin to speak to me.
It’s a dialogue we have while we're together.
We approach it discreetly.
We are starting to have an oxidative tissue exchange now.
I’m not yet in depth.
I am still on the surface.
Ah, there I pass.
It just showed me that I can go through the large posterior fissure
to enter this space, here we go.
It showed me a door, I can slowly start to descend, don’t
forget that this is
an area where we have concealed our sadness, a child crying in their lungs, a child
who has
recurrent bronchitis or asthma. Sometimes when you have pneumonia or bronchitis
you
internalize sadness and it’s a way to express it because
you don’t know
how to cry. Here I am on another level.
Now, I'm letting the body work.
You are really on an axis.
Earlier, it was more about fluidity, vascular.
And now, I’m on this axis.
And on an axis.
There, the body is searching.
It will simply...
This means it can reorganize.
We can start to release things, if you know.
And then, you can take a journey sometimes,
because you enter a somatopleural tissue
which is a tissue continuity.
This can indicate the symbolism.
of the body. The costo-pleuro-pulmonary recesses which are sacs
of exudative accumulation
transpleural, transperitoneal. So these are places where the
waste from the lung settles.
These are areas of lesser mobility. They need to be energized, they need to be released. There are
little
holes here that accumulated in these spaces. Thus, this exudate is
to say sticky liquid.
mucous, gelatinous, lymphatic.
Also, don’t forget the importance of this suspended lung,
therefore learning to adequately clear the lung regarding its attachment points,
vertebral, transverse, costopleural,
what we call the suspensory ligaments of the pleural dome.
You have what we call these recesses,
known as the costodiaphragmatic recesses,
but there is another important recess,
called the phrenomediastinal recess,
which is related to the heart, here.
This area here, and this lung,
is an important recess for the freedom of my mediastinum,
the freedom of the heart.
Here we have the pulmonary hilum,
which is really the point of relationship
with its embryonic fulcrum.
Don't forget that these lines come in here,
into these spaces,
with the importance of this diaphragm.
The first...
of the amniotic fluid we see that it begins to develop from already
the
fifth week and very significantly up to the 38th week
and we can already see the appearance of surfactant starting to develop
around the 25th week to be perfectly adequate at the level
of the
38th. It is an important period for the production of amniotic fluid
as
amniotic fluid. Thus, any pulmonary-type pathology,
bronchitis, bronchiolitis,
etc. can be manifestations seeking to resolve
issues in the embryonic stage
in the form of an unspoken state expressed as a plea, as a liquid,
we cry in the lungs.